Guide to the William L. Mertz transportation collection, 1955-1990
George Mason University Libraries
- William L. Mertz transportation collection
  - Attending O and D Surveys Committee Meeting 1/9/61 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    list of attendees
  - [Mr. Mertz's] Performance Appraisal Record 7/31/85 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Tri-State Transportation Commission: Government Capital Trends 7/68 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Guidelines for the Organization of Commuter Van Programs 2/76 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Highway Assistance Programs: A Historical Perspective 2/78 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Home Interview Survey: Interviewing Procedure (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Home Interview Survey:Special Supplementary Sample Interviewing and Field Procedure Manual 9/65 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Home Interview Survey: Production and Quality Control Manual 8/66 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Improving Access to Newark Airport 11/68 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Incident Management 10/90 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Incident Management: Executive Summary 10/90 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Interregional Highways: Message form the President of the United States 1/12/44 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - An Interview with Ellis L. Armstrong 4/87 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Investigation of the Potential Electronic Computer Work Load in the Turkish General Directorate of Highways 12/58 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Journey to Work in the New York City Standard Metropolitan Statistical Area 7/20/64 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Journey to Work Trends 7/86 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Managing National Transportation Policy 5/88 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - AASHTO Policy Recommendations on the Direction of the Future Federal Surface Transportation Program 2/89 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - [AASHTO REPORT] Highway Needs, Structural Issues and Highway Operations 9/88 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - [AASHTO report] Public Transportation Needs 9/88 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - [AASHTO Report] Modal Interlink Needs for Air, Water and Rail 9/88 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - [Tri-State]Land Use Inventory Organization 1/63 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Linking America: The County Highway System 1989 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Manhattan Business District Floor Space Trends 7/67 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - Manual for the Tri-State Land Area and Floor Space Inventory 5/68 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - [GE] Manual for Traffic Assignment Programs (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Motor Carrier Safety Assistance Program fall 1989 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - [Tri-State] Measure of a Region 5/67 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Metropolitan Transportation - a program for action 2/68 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - A History of the Kansas Highway Commission 7 the Department of Transportation 12/68 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Misconceptions: A Highway Primer (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Transportation Plan for the National Capital Region 11/9 - 11/14/1959 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    Congressional Hearings before a Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems
  - Interstate Highway Stem [maps and media coverage] 1950 to 1962 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    maps and narrative material regarding the national system and highways in North Dakota, California, New York, Connecticut, Nevada, New Mexico, Vermont, South Dakota, Minnesota and Texas; a pamphlet describing the use of "Ace Joints'
  - Interstate Highway System [Maps and Media Coverage] 1957 to 1976 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Maps and reports of highways in Missouri, Illinois, Florida, Maine, Ohio, as well as progress maps of the national system from 1968 to 1976
  - Highways in the United States [status 1940 - 1965] 1940 - 1965 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Highways in the United States [historical data and training material] 1900 - 1959 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    includes hand draft of outlines for training and a copy of pages from the Yearbook of the United States Department of Agriculture, Progress of Road Building
  - HUD Correspondence and Trip Reports 1/30/69 - 12/29/69 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - DOT HUD Agreement 7/9/64 - 11/13/74 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Cutbacks in Federal Highway Program 1966 - 1970 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Interstate System 9/7/39 - 10/18/57 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    recommended routes for the Federal Interstate Program
  - Interstate Route Locations [Alabama - North Carolina] 1967 - 1974 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    maps of regions
  - Interstate Route Locations [North Dakota - Wyoming] 1962 - 1976 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    maps of regions and a discussion of the Development of Federal Policy on Highway Toll
  - Recent Studies Concerning The Role of Transportation on the Space Economy 9/59 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Ribbon Developments in the Urban Business Pattern 6/59 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - A Look at the Pan American Highway System 4/64 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Financing Street and Highway Improvements in Urban Areas 10/64 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - California Highways and Public Works 7/64 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    Articles on completion of San Diego Freeway and on the Redwood Highway
  - 1974 National Transportation Study, Manual 1: General Information 5/72 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - User Benefit in the Evaluation of Transport and Land Use Plans 1/71 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Conference on Urban Transportation Research 9/15/61 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Addresses, Speeches, Delivered by Representatives of DOT 3/10/69 - 12/7/71 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    14
  - Addresses, Speeches, Delivered by Representatives of DOT 3/15/72 - 12/3/75 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Addresses, Speeches, Delivered by Representatives of DOT 2/3/76 - 1/31//78 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Post-interstate Plan Shapes Up 5/15/69 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Connectivity of the Interstate Highway System 1/18/60 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    the problem of the analysis of transportation networks and suggested approaches through modern graph theory
  - Stewardship Report on Administration of the Federal-Aid Highway Program 1956 - 1970 4/70 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Highway Impact Zones - Some Studies and Experience [adverse effect of highway noise] 4/24/75 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Toll Financing, Benefit Districts, and the Motor Vehicle Fund 1964 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - AAA Policies: Compilation of Policy and Resolution Declarations in Effect for the Year ending 10/69 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Economic Impact of Cutbacks in [Federal Programs] 7/30/70 - 8/6/73 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Impact of Federal Construction Cutbacks - Control of Inflation 10/69- 9/71 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - DOT Efforts Regarding Inflation 2/69 -12/69 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Public Laws Effecting Federal Highways 7/11/16 - 7/13/43 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Special Study on the Interstate System within Urban Areas 12/58 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Special Study #1 Interstate System Within Urban Areas 11/18/58 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Federal-Aid for Highways in Urban Areas 3/20/47 - 11/15/50 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Federal-Aid for Highways in Urban Areas 1/29/51 - 11/8/70 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Public Road Administration: General Administrative Memoranda 5/14/38 - 7/24/51 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - General Bragdon Correspondence 2/12/59 - 11/27/59 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Bragdon Investigation of Federal Highway Program 5/18/56 - 4/27/60 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    Includes requests for information and replies regarding Administrative and Financial Aspects
  - Bragdon Report: Basic Concepts and Criteria; and Management Control 1/9/60 - 1/23/60 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    Report from Bragdon and Comments from BPR
  - Bragdon Report: Long Range Financing 1/19/60 - 3/4/60 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Laws, Acts and Congressional Documents 7/11/1916 - 8/23/68 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    includes reports from Secretary of commerce and Presidential messages
  - [Congressional] Highway Cost Allocation Study 3/4/57 - 1/23/61 - (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Reports to Congress 1/7/58 - 1/13/65 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous BPR Memoranda of Instruction 1/15/47 - 6/21/51 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous BPR Memoranda of Instruction 7/15/37 - 2/25/46 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - [Analysis and reports regarding] History of [Highway]Contract Awards 58- 12/13/60 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - [Analysis and reports regarding] History of [Highway]Contract Awards 2/3/55 - 12/31/58 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - [ Administration] of Highway Contract Awards [Reports] 11/30/45 - 9/4/56 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Consolidation of UMTA/FHWA [Urban Mass Transit Administration/Federal Highway Administration] Administrative Support Functions Feasibility Study 6/16/78 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Consolidation of UMTA/FHWA [Urban Mass Transit Administration/Federal Highway Administration] Contracting and Procurement, and Budget Functions Feasibility Study 6/16/78 and 6/8/78 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Background Data on Planning and Research Functions 12/8/36 - 1/7/65 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - The 1983 Estimate of the Cost of Completing the interstate System, Instructional Manual 4/7/82 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Draft History of Our Nation's Highways, Part II, Chapter 4, section A and B; Social, Economic and Financial Aspects of Highway Development 7/31/75, 4/17/75 and amp 7/31/75 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - First Draft, A Preliminary Evaluation of the transportation Plan by the National Capital Transportation Agency 1/15/63 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Draft History of Our Nation's Highways, Part II, Chapter 4, section D; Patterns and Trends in Highway Planning 1975 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Draft History of Our Nation's Highways, Part II, Chapter 4, section C; Highways and the National Economy 1975 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - 711 National Interstate Highways System 1945-1954 [Virginia Interstate System Files] 7/7/60 - 12/31/64 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    information provided to Mertz to support work on history of Interstate
  - 711 National Interstate Highways System 1945-1954 [Virginia Interstate System Files] 10/3/56 - 6/22/60 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - 711 National Interstate Highways System 1945-1954 [Virginia Interstate System Files] 1/17/55 - 9/10/56 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Roy T. Messer - Land Use System Service 2/25/46 - 3/6/56 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Briefing Handbook for the Secretary of Commerce 1/65 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Location, Selection, and Maintenance of Highway Guardrail and Median Barriers 1968 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - The Department of Transportation Summary of its Organization, Executive Positions, Responsibilities 7/15/66 - 12/9/66 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Department of Transportation Task Force [Establishment of DOT] 10/15/66 - 12/29/66 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 and related laws 8/13/73 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - A Ten Year National Highway Program [A Report to the President] 1/55 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - National Highway Program [message from President to Congress] 2/25/55 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Road Types Pictures (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - 711 National Interstate Highways System [Virginia Interstate Files] 3/11/49 - 12/28/54 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - 711 National Interstate Highways System 1945-1954 [Virginia Interstate Files] 3/7/49 - 8/2/45 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Statement of National Transportation Policy 9/17/75 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Trust Fund [Federal Aid] 1/57 - 1/76 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    includes "Documentation for Nomination by National Capital Section American Society of Civil Engineers of National System of Interstate and Defense Highways for ASCE "Outstanding Civil Achievement Award" for 1974
  - Apportionments of Federal Aid Funds to States by Fiscal Years 8/9/63 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - (Department of Transportation) History 10/3/1893 - 1/27/76 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence regarding writing a history of FHWY and copies of documents regarding Federal government establishment of highway agencies. Also contains pictures of Regional and District Engineers in 1951 and 1967.
  - Department of Transportation Briefing Hardbook 3/66 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Selected memos on Highway Planning 2/20/56 - 5/11/62 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - On the Evaluation of Urban Transportation Planning Theory and Technique in the United States 1981 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    Dissertation for PhD in Maryland University
  - Review of Functions Bridge Division [Manpower Utilization] 4/22/66 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - US Department of Transportation [8th Annual Report, FY 1974] 1984 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Southern California Law Review [Urban Freeways and the Interstate System] 3/76 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - The 1973 Federal-Aid Highway Act - an analysis[Federal-Aid Highway Amendments of 1974] 1/75 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Resource Book on the Federal-Aid Highway Program folder 1 of 2 9/71 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    3 part book aimed at providing citizens basic information on: (a) benefits of highways, (b) elements of highway program, and (c) case studies of individual benefits for specific sites.
  - Resource Book on the Federal-Aid Highway Program folder 2 of 2 9/71 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography for the Role of the Auto in American Life folder 1 of 3[Federal Highway Policy in the United States] 12/2/74 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography for the Role of the Auto in American Life folder 2 of 3[Federal Highway Policy in the United States] 12/2/74 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Bibliography for the Role of the Auto in American Life folder 3 of 3[Federal Highway Policy in the United States] 12/2/74 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Reimbursement Provisions and Progress 11/71 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - La Raza Unida impact on FHWA relocation assistance program 11/30/71 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Environment Guidelines - 1970 Federal - Aid highway Act 12/7/71 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Minority Employment Statistics 7/71 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Annual FHWA Meeting, Miami FL 12/4/71 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - FHWA Meeting, Houston Texas 11/5/70 - 11/6/70 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    includes pictures of participants
  - 1969 FHWA Annual Meeting 10/23/69 - 10/25/69 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - 1968 FHWA Annual meeting 11/68 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - 1967 FHWA Annual meeting 10/12/67 - 10/14/67 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Highway Research Circulars 7/67 - 9/67 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Regional Engineers' Meeting 3/9/67 - 3/10/67 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Staff minutes 1/5/67 - 1/20/67 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Bureau of Public Roads Meeting 11/25/67 - 11/28/67 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Second national Conference on Highways and Urban Development (Williamsburg Conference) 9/6/67 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Social Impact: Environmental Quality, Community Effects and Highway Transportation 11/26/66 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Implementation of Research and Development 11/22/66 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Preservation of Historical Sites 1966 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Joint Development Concept 12/19/66 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    urban transportation
  - Summary of Regional Engineer' Meeting 2/16/59 - 8/10/66 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    includes pictures of attendees
  - Bureau of Public Roads Meeting 2/15/61 - 10/2/65 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Construction Inspection Procedures 11/64 - 12/1/64 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Circular Letter to State Heads of Highway Departments in region I 8/9/65 - 8/23/65 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Material Presented at AASHO Meeting 12/7/64 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Staff Meetings 7/9/57 - 6/3/63 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Western Regional and Division Engineers' Meeting 4/20/21/61 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - A Critical Review of Public Roads Operations (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Federal highway Administrator's Staff Meeting 8/21/57 - 8/22/57 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Briefing Memorandum [Consolidation of FHWA and UMTA] 4/25/78 - 6/26/78 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Briefing Memorandum [Consolidation of FHWA and UMTA] 6/20/78 - 7/78 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - US Highways Public Roads Documents 1947 - 1960 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    requests from States and Congress for specific Inter-State Route locations and Bureau of Public Roads replies
  - National Road Bridges [Wheeling Suspension Bridge] 3/69 - 11/30/71 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Interregional Highways Message from the President of the United States 1/12/44 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - American Highways [history of highways] (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - History (BPR - FHWA) [recommended organization, functional Statements and staffing of Office of the Secretary of Transportation] 12/16/66 - 12/22/66 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Parks - Who Needs Parks? 1974 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    In defense of a park versus a highway, a collection of 31 photographs illustrating use of Riverside Park in New York City.
  - MacDonald Award 11/27/57 - 5/13/69 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    Nominations for the award. Also included is a recap of Mr. MacDonald's service to public roads.
  - Mr. Royal little File 1/14/60 - 3/18/64 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    Mr. Little made a proposal to award money to states for completing their portion of the inter-state system on time.
  - Brinkley Correspondence 10/3/62 - 11/23/62 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    Concerns false and misleading statements made on Mr. Brinkley's 10/1/62 TV show.
  - Handbook of Highway Engineering Part One (Box 47, Folder 5)
    Prepared by F.C Turner, Retired FWHA Administrator
  - Terra space Policy Feasibility Study Group 3/8/71/ - 5/5/72 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Federal highway Administration Meeting at Phoenix, Arizona 11/24/72 - 11/25/72 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    includes pictures of participants,presentations of each of the major elements of headquarters
  - Federal highway Administration Meeting at Miami Beach, Florida 12/3/71 - 12/4/71 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Includes pictures of participants, presentations of key elements of headquarters, reduction in employment ceiling and average grade
  - Readers Digest 6/5/59 - 2/3/65 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Readers digest Articles critical of FHWA program and replies
  - Highways for the National Defense 2/1/41 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Development of Interstate Highway System (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Road User and Property Taxes on Selected Vehicles 1968 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Report of Joint Board on Interstate Highways 10/30/25 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Report on Legislative Intent with Respect to the Location of Interstate Routes [in Urban Areas] September 1959 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    Includes Material on the Concept of Local Needs in Section 116 of the Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1956
  - Department of Transportation Secretary's Decision on Interstate Highway 66, Fairfax and Arlington Counties, Virginia 1/5/77 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Summary of Recommended Corridor Design Concepts District of Columbia Interstate System 1971 11/71 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    possible Interstate routes through DC
  - A Study of Airspace Utilization 6/68 - 9/4/68 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Clips from Magazines on Highways 1 of 6 1916 - 1967 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Clips from Magazines on Highways 2 of 6 1973 - 1986 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - 1971 DC Restudy Backup Material T and F File copy 1971 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Clips from Magazines on Highways 3 of 6 1899 - 10/15/86 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Clips from Magazines on Highways 4 of 6 1913 - 1986 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    includes information on early Thomas MacDonald; Alice Huyley Ramsey's cross-country drive in 1909
  - Miscellaneous Clips from Magazines on Highways 5 of 6 1910 - 1986 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    Includes information on President Eisenhower; and a 1959 Study of Metropolitan planning for Land Use and Transportation
  - Miscellaneous Clips from Magazines on Highways 6 of 6 1912 - 1986 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - 1971 DC Restudy Backup Material T and F File copy 1971 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - District of Columbia Interstate System 1970's folder 1 of 4 5/70 - 6/76 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    includes information on "Metro" construction progress
  - District of Columbia Interstate System 1970's folder 2 of 4 2/22/70 - 8/9/74 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - District of Columbia Interstate System 1970's folder 3 of 4 1971 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Maryland Planning documents
  - The Trailblazers 1976 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    Short personal narratives by Federal highway construction personnel including human aspects of construction
  - District of Columbia Interstate System - 1970's folder 4 of 4 1972 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    includes a large map of the area
  - Instructional Memo's folder 1 of 2 8/62 - 3/19/65 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Instructional Memo's folder 2 of 2 8/62 - 9/65 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - The Diversion Problems and Its Solution Legislative background, Legal and Financial Aspects... [and Need of Protecting Highway Users from Excessive Taxation (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Diversion of highway tax funds to other purposes
  - United States Department of Agriculture Records [Bureau of Public Roads Policy Memorandum] 1 of 2 1936 - 1938 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - United States Department of Agriculture Records [Bureau of Public Roads Policy Memorandum] 2 of 2 1936 - 1938 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Siegle's Preliminary Draft of Preliminary Report on Highways folder 1 of 2 1/16/39 - 5/13/39 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Siegle's Preliminary Draft of Preliminary Report on Highways folder 2 of 2 5/13/39 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Interstate System 1000 Mile Addition, Maps Showing Proposed Urban Routes (Box 52, Folder 1)
    the Additional 1,000 miles was authorized by the 1956 Act
  - Proposed Intercity Interstate Route Chargeable against Additional 1000 miles (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - US Department of Transportation Memorandum [ FHWA Historic Artifacts] 4/2/75 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    included Original Motor Carrier Safety Regulations issued in 1939 and first codified Motor Carrier Safety Regulations
  - Miscellaneous Materials on History of Roads #2 folder 1 of 2 1/34 - 2/77 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Materials on History of Roads #2 folder 2 of 2 1899 - 7/76 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Abstracts from "American Highways" 1919 - 1956 folder 1 of 2 12/19 - 7/43 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Abstracts from "American Highways" 1919 - 1956 folder 2 of 2 1/44 - 10/55 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Origins of the Interstate (Box 53, Folder 3)
    a manuscript by Mertz
  - The Bragdon Committee (Box 53, Folder 4)
    A monograph written by Mertz summarizing the critical investigation of the Federal Interstate program by a committee appointed by President Eisenhower.
  - Office of Planning and Policy Development Biblio Database (Box 53, Folder 5)
    abstracts of Federal law regarding roads
  - Congressional hearings 1953 - 1956 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Abstracts of Thomas MacDonald's Speeches 1919 - 1931 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Abstracts of Thomas MacDonald's Speeches 1940 - 1953 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Federal Laws, Regulations and Material Relating to the Federal Highway Administration 4/70 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - A Policy on Criteria for Marking and Signing No Passing Zones On Two and three Lane Highways 1940 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - A Policy on Highway Classification [AASHO] 1940 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Policy On Maximum Dimensions and Weights Of Motor Vehicles to Be Operated Over the Highways of the United States 12/7/64 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Policy Concerning Maximum Dimensions, Weights and Speeds Of Motor Vehicles to Be Operated Over the Highways of the United States 4/1/46 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - A Policy on Sight Distances For Highways 1940 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Review of Federal-Aid Highway Programs [FHWY] 1/70 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Urban Transportation Policies and Activities 6/72 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - General Documents, etc Regarding Interstate System 8/3/47 - 4/27/66 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Mileage Status Summary Legal System of Interstate 1/2/57 - 2/17/71 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Interstate System 1947- 1966 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Federal Laws Regulations and Materials Relating to the Federal Highway Administration 10/1983 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    complied by Department of Transportation
  - The Freeway in the City 5/1/68 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    A Report to the Secretary of transportation from Urban Advisors, a group appointed by the Secretary
  - assessment of Houston Airport Wedway Automated Transit System April 1983 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    A report prepared for the Department of Transportation
  - Stars AC Propulsion Project 8/85 (Box 56, Folder 1)